<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Prologue of the Catechism of the Catholic Church</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>published June 25th,1992</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The prologue is the shortest and first section of the catechism. </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Prologue</p>
         <milestone unit="page1"/>
         <p><q>"FATHER,... this is eternal life, that they may know you, the only true God, and
               Jesus Christ whom you have sent."</q>1 <q>"God our Saviour desires all men to be
               saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth."</q> 2 <q>"There is no other name
               under heaven given among men by which we must be saved"</q>3 - than the name of
            JESUS.</p>
         <p>1 <desc source="Bible">Jn 17 3</desc>
         </p>
         <p>2 <desc source="Bible">1 Tim 2:3-4</desc></p>
         <p>3 <desc source="Bible">Acts 4:12</desc></p>
         <milestone unit="page2"/>
         <p style="title">The life of man- to know and love God</p>
         <p> God, infinitely perfect and blessed in himself, in a plan of sheer goodness freely
            created man to make him share in his own blessed life. For this reason, at every time
            and in every place, God draws close to man. He calls man to seek him, to know him, to
            love him with all his strength. He calls together all men, scattered and divided by sin,
            into the unity of his family, the Church. To accomplish this, when the fullness of time
            had come, God sent his Son as Redeemer and Saviour. In his Son and through him, he
            invites men to become, in the Holy Spirit, his adopted children and thus heirs of his
            blessed life.</p>
         <p>So that this call should resound throughout the world, Christ sent forth the apostles he
            had chosen, commissioning them to proclaim the gospel: "Go therefore and make disciples
            of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy
            Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you; and lo, I am with you
            always, to the close of the age."4 Strengthened by this mission, the apostles "went
            forth and preached everywhere, while the Lord worked with them and confirmed the message
            by the signs that attended it."5</p>
         <p>Those who with God's help have welcomed Christ's call and freely responded to it are
            urged on by love of Christ to proclaim the Good News everywhere in the world. This
            treasure, received from the apostles, has been faithfully guarded by their successors.
            All Christ's faithful are called to hand it on from generation to generation, by
            professing the faith, by living it in fraternal sharing, and by celebrating it in
            liturgy and prayer.6</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
