<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Prologue of the Catechism of the Catholic Church</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>published June 25th,1992</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The prologue is the shortest and first section of the catechism. </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Prologue</p>
         <milestone unit="page1"/>
         <p><q>"FATHER,... this is eternal life, that they may know you, the only true God, and
               Jesus Christ whom you have sent."</q>1 <q>"God our Saviour desires all men to be
               saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth."</q> 2 <q>"There is no other name
               under heaven given among men by which we must be saved"</q>3 - than the name of
            JESUS.</p>
         <p>1 <desc source="Bible">Jn 17 3</desc>
         </p>
         <p>2 <desc source="Bible">1 Tim 2:3-4</desc></p>
         <p>3 <desc source="Bible">Acts 4:12</desc></p>
         <milestone unit="page2"/>
         <p style="title">The life of man- to know and love God</p>
         <p> God, infinitely perfect and blessed in himself, in a plan of sheer goodness freely
            created man to make him share in his own blessed life. For this reason, at every time
            and in every place, God draws close to man. He calls man to seek him, to know him, to
            love him with all his strength. He calls together all men, scattered and divided by sin,
            into the unity of his family, the Church. To accomplish this, when the fullness of time
            had come, God sent his Son as Redeemer and Saviour. In his Son and through him, he
            invites men to become, in the Holy Spirit, his adopted children and thus heirs of his
            blessed life.</p>
         <p>So that this call should resound throughout the world, Christ sent forth the apostles he
            had chosen, commissioning them to proclaim the gospel: "Go therefore and make disciples
            of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy
            Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you; and lo, I am with you
            always, to the close of the age."4 Strengthened by this mission, the apostles "went
            forth and preached everywhere, while the Lord worked with them and confirmed the message
            by the signs that attended it."5</p>
         <p>Those who with God's help have welcomed Christ's call and freely responded to it are
            urged on by love of Christ to proclaim the Good News everywhere in the world. This
            treasure, received from the apostles, has been faithfully guarded by their successors.
            All Christ's faithful are called to hand it on from generation to generation, by
            professing the faith, by living it in fraternal sharing, and by celebrating it in
            liturgy and prayer.6</p>
         <milestone unit="page2"/>
         <p>II. Handing on the Faith: Catechesis</p>
         <p>4 Quite early on, the name catechesis was given to the totality of the Church's efforts
            to make disciples, to help men believe that Jesus is the Son of God so that believing
            they might have life in his name, and to educate and instruct them in this life, thus
            building up the body of Christ.7</p>
         <p>5<q> "Catechesis is an education in the faith of children, young people and adults which
               includes especially the teaching of Christian doctrine imparted, generally speaking,
               in an organic and systematic way, with a view to initiating the hearers into the
               fullness of Christian life."</q>8</p>
         <p>6 While not being formally identified with them, catechesis is built on a certain number
            of elements of the Church's pastoral mission which have a catechetical aspect, that
            prepare for catechesis, or spring from it. They are: the initial proclamation of the
            Gospel or missionary preaching to arouse faith; examination of the reasons for belief;
            experience of Christian living; celebration of the sacraments; integration into the
            ecclesial community; and apostolic and missionary witness.9</p>
         <p>7 <q>"Catechesis is intimately bound up with the whole of the Church's life. Not only
               her geographical extension and numerical increase, but even more her inner growth and
               correspondence with God's plan depend essentially on catechesis."10 </q></p>
         <p>8 Periods of renewal in the Church are also intense moments of catechesis. In the great
            era of the Fathers of the Church, saintly bishops devoted an important part of their
            ministry to catechesis. <persName type="saint">St. Cyril of Jerusalem</persName> and
               <persName type="saint">St. John Chrysostom</persName>, <persName type="saint">St.
               Ambrose</persName> and <persName type="saint">St. Augustine</persName>, and many
            other Fathers wrote catechetical works that remain models for us.11 </p>
         <p>9 "The ministry of catechesis draws ever fresh energy from the councils. the Council of
            Trent is a noteworthy example of this. It gave catechesis priority in its constitutions
            and decrees. It lies at the origin of the Roman Catechism, which is also known by the
            name of that council and which is a work of the first rank as a summary of Christian
            teaching. . "12 The <name type="council">Council of Trent</name> initiated a remarkable
            organization of the Church's catechesis. Thanks to the work of holy bishops and
            theologians such as <persName type="saint">St. Peter Canisius</persName>, <persName
               type="saint">St. Charles Borromeo</persName>, <persName type="saint">St. Turibius of
               Mongrovejo</persName> or <persName type="saint">St. Robert Bellarmine</persName>, it
            occasioned the publication of numerous catechisms. </p>
         <p>10 It is therefore no surprise that catechesis in the Church has again attracted
            attention in the wake of the <name type="council">Second Vatican Council</name>, which
               <persName type="saint">Pope Paul Vl</persName> considered the great catechism of
            modern times. the General Catechetical Directory (1971) the sessions of the Synod of
            Bishops devoted to evangelization (1974) and catechesis (1977), the apostolic
            exhortations Evangelii nuntiandi (1975) and Catechesi tradendae (1979), attest to this.
            the Extraordinary Synod of Bishops in 1985 asked "that a catechism or compendium of all
            Catholic doctrine regarding both faith and morals be composed"13 The Holy Father, Pope
            John Paul II, made the Synod's wish his own, acknowledging that "this desire wholly
            corresponds to a real need of the universal Church and of the particular Churches."14 He
            set in motion everything needed to carry out the Synod Fathers' wish. </p>
         <p>11 This catechism aims at presenting an organic synthesis of the essential and
            fundamental contents of Catholic doctrine, as regards both faith and morals, in the
            light of the Second Vatican Council and the whole of the Church's Tradition. Its
            principal sources are the Sacred Scriptures, the Fathers of the Church, the liturgy, and
            the Church's Magisterium. It is intended to serve "as a point of reference for the
            catechisms or compendia that are composed in the various countries".15</p>
         <p>12 This work is intended primarily for those responsible for catechesis: first of all
            the <roleName type="clergy">bishops</roleName>, as teachers of the faith and pastors of the Church. It is offered to them
            as an instrument in fulfilling their responsibility of teaching the People of God.
            Through the <roleName type="clergy">bishops</roleName>, it is addressed to redactors of catechisms, to <roleName type="clergy">priests</roleName>, and to
            catechists. It will also be useful reading for all other Christian faithful. </p>
         <p></p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
